noacsc.org 2018-11-05

# 

                                     Customer Privacy Notice
Ohio Information Technology Centers (“ITCs”) provide IT shared services to Ohio K-12 schools
and libraries (“Customers”). The ITCs provide their Customers with two services governed by
Section 222 of the Communications Act of 1934 (the “Communications Act”) – Broadband
Internet access (“Internet Service”) and telephony services (Telephony Service”). In addition to
these services, the ITCs provide services including accounting, payroll, library automation,
EMIS, network management, student information systems, video, remote distance learning,
electronic resources, computerized grade book, parental access, Web conferencing, web and
email filtering, firewall and Web security, Web hosting, server hosting, and a data-driven
decision report (collectively these services, along with Internet Service and Telephony Service,
shall be referred to as the “Services”).
The following Customer Privacy Notice (“Notice”) applies to Customers of the Services
provided by the Northwest Ohio Area Computer Services Cooperative (NOACSC). We use the
words “Customer,” “you” or “your” to refer to any Customer of the Services. As part of the
provision of the Services, we obtain information about you and your use of the Services.
NOACSC is committed to securely maintaining our Customers’ information. This Notice will
identify our policies regarding the collection, retention, use and disclosure of that information.
To be clear, this Notice only applies to information obtained through NOACSC’s provision of
the Services.
We may update this Notice from time to time as we deem appropriate and will post any updates
on our website. You can access the most recent version of this Notice by visiting
www.noacsc.org.
                                       Customer Information
When a Customer uses the Services, NOACSC may transmit, store and/or maintain information,
on the Customer’s behalf. This information may come directly from the Customer or through a
Customer’s use of the Services. Some of the information may be “personally identifiable
information” (“PII”), meaning information that identifies an individual or can be reasonably used
to identify an individual. Examples of personally identifiable information include names, street
addresses, telephone numbers, taxpayer identification numbers (“TIN”), social security numbers
or email addresses. It could also include information that is linked or associated with a particular
individual. Personally identifiable information does not include de-identified, anonymous, or
aggregate data that does not identify an individual. For example, information regarding an
individual’s age would only be considered personally identifiable information if it was linked or
combined with an individual’s name, address or other identifying information.
When you utilize our Services, you may transmit or provide us with both PII and non-PII. This
information includes, but is not limited to: name, physical address, billing address, telephone
numbers, social security numbers, taxpayer identification numbers, driver’s license numbers,
user IDs, email addresses, and credit card numbers. In addition, you may provide us with
information regarding Customer demographics, billing history, payment history, service history,
equipment type, equipment serial number, equipment settings, equipment configuration, and
software information.

NOACSC also receives information known as “customer proprietary network information” or
“CPNI.” CPNI generally relates to the quantity, technical configuration, type, destination,
location and amount of your use of our Services that we receive by virtue of your relationship
with us as an Internet Service or Telephony Service Customer. CPNI also includes information
in your bills related to your Service.
Internet Service
As part of the provision of Internet Service, NOACSC may receive and maintain certain
information pertaining to the service, which may include a customer device’s media access
control (“MAC”) addresses, Internet Protocol (“IP”) addresses, uniform resource locator
(“URL”) history, date and time of connections, volume of data transmitted and received, network
activity, network traffic, data transmission rates and latencies, location information, security
characteristics, and other Internet performance information. NOACSC also may collect
information regarding bandwidth, usage, transmissions and content for purposes of protecting the
integrity of the network. That information, when linked to identifying information such as a
name, physical address or telephone number, may be considered CPNI. We will take reasonable,
good faith steps to protect any such information that may be considered CPNI.
Telephony Service
We provide Telephone Service utilizing facilities-based “voice over Internet protocol” (“VoIP”).
As part of the provision of Telephone Service we may be provided information from our
Customers such as names, physical addresses and telephone numbers. We also collect
information about the quality, configuration, location, and use of your Telephone Service and
information regarding your level of Service and features that you use. That information, when
linked to identifying information such as your name, physical address or telephone number is
considered CPNI.
                                   Information Use and Disclosure
NOACSC collects and maintains the information described herein for the purpose of
implementing, managing, and improving the services provided by NOACSC. We may use such
information to monitor for, detect, and protect against unauthorized use of the Services.
The information described herein is considered the Customer’s property, not NOACSC’s
property. As such, NOACSC will not sell customer’s information to any person or entity for any
purpose. NOACSC may use, disclose or permit access to your PII, CPNI or other information it
collects and maintains with another entity: (1) when necessary for the purposes of conducting a
business activity related to your Service; (2) to protect our rights or property; (3) to protect users
of our Services from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful use of the Services; (4) as required by law,
including, but not limited to, Ohio’s public record laws; or (5) with your approval.
As part of the provision of the Services, NOACSC may have access to or acquire student
information protected by the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (20 U.S.C. 1232 and its
regulations) and Ohio Revised Code Section 3319.321. NOACSC will abide by the applicable
requirements for disclosure of any information regulated by these statutes.

Additionally, NOACSC may be required to disclose PII to governmental entities or comply with
formal legal requests for information from non-governmental entities. In these instances,
NOACSC may be required to disclose PII pursuant to a court order or with your consent.
                                       Securing Your Information
NOACSC follows industry-standard practices to protect against the loss, misuse or unauthorized
access to your PII or CPNI. However, we cannot guarantee that our practices will prevent every
unauthorized attempt to access, use or disclose such information.
                                     Customer Access to Information
You may check the accuracy of personal information in your account by contacting us directly at
419-228-7417. You may make a more thorough examination of the records containing your PII
at our office during business hours and at your own cost and upon reasonable prior notice to us.
If you wish to examine these records, please contact our office.
                                                Retention
All information obtained shall be stored in accordance with industry standard practices and in
accordance with the appropriate, current Ohio Administrative Code which defines ITC
operations. NOACSC shall maintain all information related to E-Rate discounts for ten years
after the latter of the last day of the applicable funding year, or the service delivery deadline for
the funding request. In cases where an E-rate discount is subject to review by the Federal
Communications Commission or the Universal Service Administrative Company, NOACSC will
retain information related to the discounted Service for the required document retention period.
Information obtained for Services provided outside of the E-rate program shall be maintained in
NOACSC regular business records as long as you are a Customer or until no longer needed for
business, tax, or legal purposes.
                                       Enforcement of Your Rights
Federal law (including 47 U.S.C. §222) limits the information a telephony and broadband
provider may collect, maintain, use and share. You may enforce your rights concerning our
collection, maintenance, use and any unauthorized sharing of your CPNI or PII. Among your
remedies is the right to seek damages and reasonable costs and attorneys’ fees.
                                    Questions Regarding This Policy
If you have any questions about this Notice, please contact us at 419-228-7417.
